# **Skyler Schuck**

skyler.schuck@colostate.edu | skylerschuck.github.io | linkedin.com/in/skyler-schuck/

## **About Me**

Experience in information technology, data science, and applied economic analysis. A seasoned user in R, SQL, Python. My research interests include regional analysis and improving rural outcomes. Most of my projects are centered around creating data/information systems and tools to support my research.

## **Education**

2021 – Present	M.S., Agricultural and Resource Economics, Colorado State University Anticipated graduation in Spring 2023, GPA: 3.7
2017 - 2021	<b>B.A., Economics,</b> <i>California Lutheran University</i> Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.8
2017 - 2021	<b>B.S., Computer Information Systems,</b> <i>California Lutheran University</i> Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.8

Professional Experience				
01/2022 – Present Denver, CO	<b>Data Science Intern,</b> <i>City and County of Denver</i> Housed in the Department of Finance as a part of the Professional Technical Intern Program, I assist with inter-agency reporting and data analysis. Report to the Chief Economist for the City.			
08/2021 – Present Fort Collins, CO	Graduate Research Assistant, Colorado State Univesity  Apart of the Regional Economic Development Institute (REDI) at CSU. Generate regional economic analysis for on-going projects and as-needed when requested by City/County/State Agencies.  Leading website re-design project for more interactive and engaging experience.			
03/2021 – 07/2021 Westlake Village, CA	IT Technician I/IT Specialist, River Oaks Academy Provided all operational technology support of the Charter School across two campuses including: Computer tech support and maintenance, Student registration: system support and use, Software and hardware support: troubleshooting and installation, GSuite Administration, Website and social media management, Network management (Cisco Meraki), Photo, video & sound editing (Adobe CC).			
01/2018 – 04/2021 Thousand Oaks, CA	IT Technician (Student), California Lutheran University  Faced the full spectrum of technological challenges at the University, ranging from helping professors in their laboratories and offices as well as providing classroom technology support. This meant quickly assessing challenges, and offering technology solutions in a broad range of time-sensitive situations. Furthermore, given the fluid population and needs of the University, constantly bonding well with new team members and quickly adapting and integrating new skills.			
05/2020 – 08/2020 McMinnville, OR	<b>Groundskeeper,</b> Linfield University			
08/2017 – 08/2019 McMinnville, OR	<b>Director of Counselor Development,</b> 4-H Yamhill County Extension Office, Oregon State University Worked for local 4-H Extension's Summer Camps. We met many times throughout the year in order to plan each year's camps. I was a leader in the group and I was often tasked with organizing			

activities and event planning for all leadership staff.

## **Publications**

12/2021 Fishers Peak State Park: Evaluating a New Natural Amenity in Southern Colorado,

REDI@CSU 🛮

The recently christened Fishers Peak State Park offers great potential to give a much-needed boost to the economy of Las Animas County, specifically the town of Trinidad.

## Skills

<b>R</b> R Shiny, Economic Analysis, Data Analysis	••••	<b>Python</b> Pandas, Pystat	• • • • •
<b>SQL</b> <i>MySQL, PostgreSQL</i>	••••	<b>Web Development</b> <i>HTML/CSS/JS</i>	• • • • •
PowerBI	• • • • •	Tableau	• • • • •

### Courses

**Applied Microeconomic Theory,** Colorado State University

**Applied Econometics,** Colorado State University

**Quantitative Methods,** Colorado State University

**Applied Welfare and Policy Analysis,** *Colorado State University* 

**Environmental and Natural Resource Economics,** *Colorado State University* 

**Applied Advanced Water Resource Economics,** *Colorado State University* 

**Database Management Systems,** California Lutheran University

**Software Engineering,** California Lutheran University

**Systems Analysis,** California Lutheran University

**Information, Systems, and Organizational Design,** California Lutheran University

**Data Analysis with R,** California Lutheran University

**Calculus II,** California Lutheran University

**Linear Algebra,** California Lutheran University